AUSTIN RODRIGUES

iOS Engineer

CONTACT

√ Los Angeles, CA 90045

& 808-292-6576

☑ <u>austin.da.rodrigues@gmail.com</u>

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/austin-rodrigues-a09230103/

https://github.com/AustinAukai

https://austinaukai.com/

EDUCATION

Santa Clara University

BS Civil Engineering

University of California, Los Angeles

Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certificate

SKILLS

iOS Development

Swift 5.0

SwiftUI

Programmatic UI

UI/UX Programming

Firebase Cloud Firestore

Cocoapod Dependancies

Web Development

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Material-UI, Bootstrap, jQuery, Node, Express, SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose

ABOUT

After a 3 year career in Civil Engineering and Project Management, I decided to explore iOS Engineering. I am efficient at integrating problem solving and intuitive design to develop applications that put the user first. Acknowledged for having strong communication skills and leadership qualities.

EXPERIENCE

Hike Intel

iOS Engineer Intern - Sep 2020 - Feb 2021

Assisted the lead engineer with UI programming on parts of the Hike Intel app. Used SwiftUI to properly program screens' navigation and save user information, both locally and cloud based. Built certain screens from scratch when given a design and a guideline for functionality. More information in Project/Apps section.

PCL Construction

Project Engineer - Sep 2018 - Oct 2019

Assisted the Project Manager with managing construction workers and management team. Completed take offs, bid analysis, plan updating both digitally and on hard copies, requests for information (RFI), submittals, procurements, change and purchase orders, quality plant visits, site walks, safety inspections, and preconstruction design coordination.

Shangri-LA Construction

Project Engineer - Sep 2017 - Sep 2018

Assisted the Project Manager with meeting minutes and managing construction workers. Completed take offs, bid analysis, plan updating, requests for information (RFI), submittals, procurements, punch lists, and Owner-Architect-Contractor (OAC) meetings.

SC Builders

Project Engineer - Sep 2016 - Sep 2017

Completed take offs, bid analysis, plan updating, requests for information (RFI), submittals, and LEED Certification (LEED Gold).

AUSTIN RODRIGUES

iOS Engineer

PROJECTS/APPS

Hike Intel

🖨 https://apps.apple.com/bh/app/hike-intel-trail-conditions/id1525174899

- Hike Intel is an app for hiking and adventure enthusiasts alike. The app allows users to look up information about hikes and see what the current conditions are. Users can also post information about a hiking trail if there is something other hikers need to know about ie. icy conditions, a tree blockage, etc. This app can also be used for guidance to help hikers successfully navigate trails safely.
- Only iOS Engineer intern that helped the Lead Engineer with tasks such as UI programming, firebase storage programming, writing code to navigate between screens while having data persistence, programming three screens from scratch using a design and functionality guidelines, programming the functionality for feedback to the app owner, and programming the saving of user information, locally and cloud based.
- SwiftUI, Firebase Cloud Firestore

Fitmoodji

https://github.com/AustinAukai/Fitmoodji

https://fitmoodji.herokuapp.com/

- Fitmoodji is a fitness app that provides the user randomly generated workouts that will be logged within the app. The user is assigned an animated emoji mood that dynamically changes depending on the user's daily fitness activity.
- One of two Front-End Developers with responsibilities including all mobile/web design, front-end routes, connecting front-end to back-end, and using React to create an organized component driven app.
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Material-UI, Express, Node, MongoDB

Quiz Mania

https://github.com/AustinAukai/QuizMania

🖨 https://quizmaniaapp.herokuapp.com/

- Quiz Mania is a math quiz game for kids that randomly generates questions for the user to answer. This app allows users to challenge another user to see who gets the most questions right.
- One of two Back-End Developers with responsibilities including routing our API to the front-end, setting up the app databases, and writing an algorithm to randomly generate math questions.
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bulma, Express, Node, MySQL

Calorie Companion

https://github.com/AustinAukai/Calorie-Companion

https://austinaukai.github.io/Calorie-Companion/

- Calorie Companion is an app that allows users to find nearby restaurants that display the caloric values for their menu items. The app is also a calorie counter.
- Responsibilities included overall web/mobile design and structure of the app and support in JavaScript logic.
- HTML5, CSS3, Materialize, JavaScript, jQuery